All right, cool. So that's the final version, yeah?
Yeah.
So we discussed how this is wrong.
Yeah, I...
Oh, did I not change it?
Market limit to... Market limit, order ratio. Yeah, you did change, actually. It's good.
So, yeah, if anything comes up, that isn't correct, just change it, and then you should want to save this into whatever folder you would be making.
Yeah, you make a folder, yeah.
Is this done on the iPad?
No, this is done on my Mac.
Okay.
All right, I'm just questioning.
Yeah, I've just annotated it on the trading view.
All right.
So there's one, there's two small area of weak and southern south side,
couple with the relative market order buy volume,
relatively bigger or greater market order by volume.
Bigger, okay.
All right, so first deal receives order from client.
Shit, just spilt coffee, bro.
On yourself?
Nah.
On your desk?
Yeah, normally, it'll be all right.
It's only a small amount.
as long as it's not on your computer or anything
then you'll be all right
so first dealer receives order from client
withdraw sell liquidity from the market
okay so you did correct that
this probably is a misnomer
it's inaccurate to say that the deal is
withdrawing sell liquidity from the market
themselves they're not willing to take the opposite side
because of their likelihood of them
not being able to trade out of any short position they take on
without taking a loss
so their willingness to go short
and provide liquidity that level is like not present.
It's not necessarily withdrawing liquidity,
but other other LPs do.
Other RELPs actually control the supply liquidity
as we discussed before,
but that receiving dealer who's eternalizing the flow
just simply decides not to go against it.
Okay, so how would I correct that would say
his win next to go short is?
He's avoiding adverse selection.
He doesn't want a long order volume shot
to push price against him.
Because if that's the case,
Imagine I came and I sold you a shit car, you buy it.
You've basically been selected adversely.
You're holding an asset that's shit.
You're going to lose on it.
So in order to avoid adverse selection,
the dealer will avoid taking on short positions in that specific environment
of volume surge coupled with sell liquidity weakness.
So you can just say like avoids taking on shorts.
Yeah, I've just wrote it down and I'll correct it.
So we can, until you can find out of sell liquidity from client.
and the book perfect another point right how does the dealer have awareness or how does the dealer know
that there's weak sell liquidity in the market these guys are analyst so as a dealer yourself or as a
liquidity provider you first of all have to keep prices the same as all the other LPs right
yeah yeah in order to avoid getting in order to avoid getting picked off so dealers are constantly
constantly looking at the updates from other LPs of prices number one yeah it's all done
on an automated basis. And number two, they're
connected to, they're typically connected to
other third party venues where multiple
dealers quote as well. Okay.
So this is done all via algorithm, isn't it?
What is? The
keeping prices the same and
Yeah, yeah, yeah, all of this is algorithm.
It's all automated. It's all automated.
They built
they build trading engines, which are just
pieces of software,
where financial
information can cross, like
trade data,
literally just any
financial information regarding orders
order confirmations
etc is called a fixed API
financial information
exchange and they can
hook up their trading engines to all the
necessary venues and necessary
clients so that information can flow
from and to the dealer
okay
but yeah
like third parties even banks
internally have tech departments that are building these
trading engines and pricing engines
which are designed to do exactly what you're saying.
Key prices are the same, avoid adverse selection,
decide whether to take on risk,
hedge out trades, internalize and match orders, et cetera,
it's all automated,
but there'll be a person or two or three people
sitting at a desk overseeing
that everything's running smoothly.
Yeah, this outline has been nuts, man, honestly.
It's ridiculous.
It's mental.
So the price is pulled high,
looking to sell equity in the book.
Dealer looks in the order book.
can see sell limit orders to match it off with perfect.
Now, just to add on to this point,
the sell liquidity could be dispersed evenly.
Yeah.
So it's very unlikely, but it's a volume shot of 50 million.
It could be two, two, two, two, two, two, two, two, two, two, two, two, two, at each price level.
Yeah.
But realistically, that won't be the case.
What's often going to be, what's often going to happen is there may have been sell limit
orders here from multiple participants, from other dealers as well.
They remove them.
yeah so as volume comes through the sell equity in this instance the whole market whoever has sell equity around them avoids they always being picked off sell equity draws away from the fast moving prices it's kind of results in a self-reinforcing tabernamic where sell equity is running away by volume chasing and it gets faster but it's also not an equal distribution so you could have like hold two three pip periods where there's no sell liquidity and then a pocket of sell liquidity turns up there's also not an equal distribution so you could have like hold two three pit periods where there's no sell liquidity and then a pocket of sell liquidity turns up
there and then like two more prices where no sell liquidity is there and then two more pockets
where there is sell liquidity resulting in a price run which transacted nothing here some there
nothing here some there etc etc it's actually broken up in the way market is trading there's
actually areas within that price run where hardly any or very very little trade was facilitated
creating weakness yeah i remember you're saying actually um you you gave the example of uh price jumping 10
percent and he said that there was just no orders in that range which added up to the 10
percent exactly so the that sell liquidity not only running away but they're not only
drawing away from the volume but also being distributed quite thinly leaves a price move which
has gaps in it where no volumes transacted yeah and it's traded relatively thinly it's all
stretched out it's not efficient so the other LQ uh liquidity providers we've been to
to a protective state, they want to go short against buy volume,
assist and sell liquidity in the first place.
That's everybody, yeah?
Yeah, yeah.
They, what they don't want to do is provide sell liquidity here,
a whole bunch of sell liquidity there,
whilst this next guy is providing bi-liquity here.
Because then you could buy their, sell there, capture the difference.
Even though there might actually be sell liquidity at these levels,
they control the distribution of it.
They, they themselves would take on that risk.
that whoever's trying to sell
they would go against them
and then now they have an inventory
that they can provide
behind the ask price
as price goes up
and as they keep the same price
as the dealer
just like you said here
dealer can buy the sell limit order
so they themselves go along
this provides liquidity on the way up
this gives them an option
and inventory
just like if I want to buy something off you
you need inventory in the first place
you need the stock
they can raise that stock
by taking on
the sell equity
sitting in the boat
realistically what they're doing
is they are stopping
that sell liquidity
which could stabilize
this buying phase
they're stopping it
from reaching the market
not necessarily
because they're evil
they can't have to keep prices
the same
it's the structure of the market
it makes them
it's like a prisoner's dilemma
right
they can either
provide that sell equity
out to the market
and get picked off
or they can control it
trying to cut their losses.
So price moves a less liquid side
and stretches further than it should
resulting in thin and efficient.
Yeah, that's perfect.
So buy volume dries off.
Oh shit.
Price leaves vacuum behind of thin liquidity.
Try to elaborate on that what that means.
Buy volume dries off, weak by liquidity.
So this point in saying price goes
a less liquid side
eventually also applies
to price going down as well.
Yeah, because it's traded thing on the way up as well, isn't it?
Yeah.
And the real volume.
The real liquidity maintains back down.
at the origin
what I want you to do then
is you understand this
you need to now validate it
based on your own observation so
it's quite a simple one
you can go back in your charts
on your board
identify the origins
and price will tip like a very
very very high
percent of the time
it will respond off the core areas
yeah this one actually
did it came down lower on
this chart and then it went all the way back up yeah uh even you could make the argument that
this was the core area of this price run down why we need to notice is on the way up there was
hardly any selling but there was a one there was a there was a response yeah as it came back
to the core i know it was a great response and price ended up going through it but that was still a
response there's always a high level of certainty or there's a high certainty of response at
core areas.
One of the ways to think about this is the market's efficient as in there's a whole lot of
liquidity in FX is provided quite successfully on a day-to-day basis.
So over a time span as long as, or sorry, as short as, I don't know, 12 hours, the FX
market is very, very liquid.
Very liquid.
It's very efficient in providing and those who sell liquidity, they provision it really quite
well. Those who buy it get to access it really quite well. So what you get is, so not only is it
highly liquid, but there's two-sided liquidity. There's a high level of natural demand from
FX liquidity. So there's sellers of GDP, there's buyers of GDP and vice versa for USD, right? That's
relentless as well. So there's a high level of natural demand. And whilst this is relatively
or broadly efficient, on an intraday micro basis,
a micro-volatility basis.
So you say like lower timeframes?
Yeah, basically.
On a much, much shorter scale,
at any given point,
the market can become super inefficient.
So within this 12-hour period,
the market is very stable.
Yeah.
By the sellers were matched,
but at any individual point in time
over that 12-hour period,
on a much shorter scale,
the market can be very inefficient.
price can be
volume can find it very hard
to find liquidity
liquidity can draw away
create those weaknesses
create those inefficiencies
which of course we know what happens
it creates that sequence of events
where you have stability
volume shot
efficient price run
and then a subsequent exhaustion and fill
all right
so you have stability
weakness on one side
volume shot sell liquidity
run by liquidity runs away
sellers chase
subsequent price move is exhausted, leaves behind that weakness, and it takes much less buying
to push price back up, back to the origin, back to where the real trading and liquidity is.
That sequence of events takes place relentlessly on every single scale, on an intraday basis
at least. This market here is very inefficient. There's hardly any trade being facilitated,
i.e. sellers aren't matching with buyers because there's hardly any bias present. So we have to
think about this and how it applies to the border market.
broadly very efficient
any individual point in time
can be super inefficient
which ultimately means
these micro inefficiencies
will end up being filled
with a high level of reliability
because at these areas
strong liquidity turns up
it's not like buying
continues and continues and continues
and sellers continue running away
it's just for relatively short periods of time
where you see a lack of liquidity
volume causing price to stretch out
further than it should
But over a long enough period, it's nice and stable.
Okay.
If I said this, if that's the case, what do you think the likelihood is then of this price
run inefficiency to the downside?
Is it likely to continue selling off or is it likely to draw back into the range and stabilize?
Yeah, draw back in and stabilize.
Because of this super efficient nature of prices over a big enough time span.
But like I said, on an individual basis, the microstructural,
So not a microstructure, yeah, the microstructure and the behavior of equity providers can create these small, uh, weak areas of trading.
Yeah.
So it's unique in that sense.
You could categorize the market as efficiently inefficient.
So the market is inefficient in these areas, but it does it quite efficiently.
The market doesn't stay inefficient and creates these like super aggressive, one-directional, mad volatile moves.
It doesn't move 10, 20% in the day, like some.
crypto shit coins
the trade is
facilitated quite well
over a big enough time span
but on a
like I just said
on a much shorter basis
it can result in the weaknesses
that's good for us
because there's opportunity
where there's an efficiency
I'll give you an example
in tennis
have I give you this example before
I haven't heard of an example with tennis
so there's an inefficiency
in the way betting is facilitated
on tennis, in tennis at least.
If me and you sit at the court,
Raphael scores a point,
the umpire has to update that point
into his computer.
Imagine the umpire takes 30 seconds
to update that point.
But I am on the phone to you
and I tell you within two seconds.
You now have information about the tennis game
which the bet makers,
the odds setters, haven't yet updated
because the umpire hasn't updated
the score yet.
Did you get it?
Yeah.
because of how slow this umpire is there's a guaranteed edge highly highly probable edge that mean you can exploit that in efficiency and place the bet before the odds are updated the odds are updated too slow because this umpire is too slow that's called court siding it's legal it's not illegal but the tennis uh venue will throw you out if they find you on your phone really you can't be in your phone at all no no no if you're on the phone and they have to
people looking out for court-siders, basically. If they suspect that you're a court-side-in,
don't throw you out. If there's weakness in buy limits, it doesn't take that much market-order
sellers to push through that area, marketing the order ratio. So not only can we identify
broader inefficiencies which result in longer duration price moves, you know, price could
move down for the whole day, two days, it could move down for three hours. We don't know. The
duration of the move could be long-winded or long-lasting relative to the, you know, relative.
But the entry point, we can also identify where the highest probability entries are, you know,
a.k.a. the point of exhaustion. So it helps us, like, structure out our trade plan in
appropriate ways, identifying why price behaves the way it does, where there's edge in trading
price the way it is. It's just much more appropriate. Compare that to breakout traders.
when does the break-out occur, a good majority of them fail.
So how, you know, in effect, the more efficient the market comes,
the less likely you ought to get consistent breakouts.
Hence why these breakout strategies don't work over the long run.
That's exactly why these people, that's exactly why, like,
conventional trading strategies which rely on trending states,
they're not so effective anymore.
They are effective in risk assets, like S&P 500 or,
equities and stocks
they'll be super effective in them
but something as broadly as balanced
as GDP, USD, liquidity
not so much
so again, if you wanted to be a trend trader
I'd say you're in the wrong market
maybe you can like maybe you could trade a currency
which is considered to be a risk currency
like the Australian dollar or New Zealand dollar
you could even trade
emerging market currencies like the Turkish lira
but then like with emerging market currencies
you're going to have issues with spreads and transaction costs
with these you're going to have super spiky times
in response to negative sentiment
if there was news around them too
yeah so like if there was anything that that's
considered negative broadly for the whole
you know investor psychosphere
these currencies will respond negatively as well
whereas something's really very liquid like your USD
at least it can stay protected from that
the more liquid the asset,
the more consistent in its behaviours,
the more illiquid it is,
the more easier it is for it to be one-sided.
Not even one-side.
The more like, what do you call it?
The volatility is like more,
it's like,
so there's two types of volatility.
There's volatility that's more favoured ones
take advantage of.
It price runs in specific directions,
but it's not,
unstable, right?
And then you have unstable volatility
where price can quite easily slip you
three, four, five times your risk.
So you have a 10-pips stop.
It can quite easily risk you 50 pips.
That's how illiquid these markets are.
Emergent market currencies are.
So you do have like adverse
or something like implied volatility,
which is not favorable volatility.
And then you have the microvolatility
and liquid assets
where consistently you'll get responses at levels
but inside of that you have these thin legs
which is kind of good it's kind of good
we have weakness into areas of strength
and we already know price goes to less liquid side
right you're going to have a much more consistency
in price behaviours in liquid assets
than you will in much more
much less liquid assets
anyway
what kind of time frame do you go down to
I could be looking at a three tick chart
is
or a 10 tick chart
just to see inside of here
yeah
sometimes I need a clear view
you can't really see what's going on inside that candle
it's just this big sell off
the lower time frame will give me a clear of
so sometimes you need to use a lower time frame
just like zoom in and look inside of here
we're going to be looking inside of here for multiple reasons
we want to assess the strength of this move
if I'm looking to long it
I want to be able to assess
when this movie is exhausted
none of the details
already present on a 15 million time frame here
it's just one big fuck off candle
so you need the lower time frames
to like select your trades
time your trades
avoid taking a trade
etc etc
okay
just for a clear of view
you'll come to see what I mean by that
in due time
so yeah
something that you might want to check
compare
GDP-USD consistency in
price drawing back responding off liquidity
to something illiquid
and a liquid coin
could be anything
like
a liquid asset could be
anything crypto wise
not Bitcoin Bitcoin is quite liquid right now
but any shit coin
you'll typically see that it just stabilises into nothing
shoots out
and then all it does the volume dries off
and it does absolutely nothing
all the way back down.
Well, that dodge coin,
whatever it's called.
Yeah.
So these are liquidity,
these are like liquidity events
where one-sided volume,
they're typically going to be pump and dumps as well.
So I wouldn't be surprised
if someone accumulated large amounts here
started marketing these coins.
So everybody else buys
and then they can sell into them.
They're going to be pump and dumps,
but it's probably a bit premature
for me to discuss this,
but we're in liquid assets
you're going to get consistency
in which types of levels price response off
the characteristics of what winners look like
and what losers look like
those consistencies are just not present in illiquid assets
price is just going to be super volatile
it'll expand past levels
it will become
wherever you want to be trading
it's just hardly liquid enough
for you to even get a fill on your trades
so you can't really trade at the point
of exhaustion, the aerobatic
peers as well, they behave less favourably
they won't behave as favourably
as these. There's a common
misconception out there, yeah, that
the more volatile asset, the better it is
but it's not true. Actually
I would make the bet
or I would make the argument
that in the last five years
being it being the lowest
volatility in major effects period, like your
USD, USD, JPI,
GBP, USD.
It's resulted in more
consistencies in price behavior it's allowed us to trade with tighter risk so i can long this
with a one two-pips stop and you know so that's two pips that that's one r per two pips and capture
much more money of smaller moves all right in a less in a less volatile environment aka more stable
you can trade with tighter risk with a higher certainty of response of these levels it allows
you to be more active in the market so you can go long and short, whereas in super volatile
environments, there's not much for you to do unless you caught that trade and unless you're
willing to buy at more and more expensive prices, which is kind of against this dynamic or this
notion of buying low and selling high. Yeah. If you can buy more and more expensive prices and then,
or unless you caught the initial move, there's nothing for you to do, bro. Yeah, in between you and
can't really be active. So I'm not against it. All I'm just saying is,
a good majority of the time, a good 70% of the time, the market's stable, 30% of the time
it's moving. It doesn't make sense, in my opinion, at least if you're an active day trader
to try and find the moving times.
You know, if you're an active trader, meaning you place more than two, three trades a day,
you want to sell a chance to be an active day trader. You don't want to be that, like, imagine
you as a swing trader. You're looking for the,
big moves, a good majority of your trades
you would have to cut early,
they wouldn't work out or materialize.
And you would only get
two to three to four good trades a month.
Assuming you're looking at one pair.
If you were
cross-analysing like
five, six, seven, 18 different pairs
and you had a short list of potential
weavers, you might
get more hits and more swing trades,
but the quality
of your entries, the quality your trades will
drop because you haven't got time to like
focus in on one.
Yeah, I understand.
So there's always a trade-off, in it?
Like, if you want higher frequency of trade, you can take shit of trades.
If you want a higher probability trade, you typically have less frequency of trades.
A lower frequency of trade.
Anyway, let's move on.
So that's that.
It's infinite and endless, this dynamic of price being relatively stable, then a surge of volume,
pushing price out, or the price becoming volatile as it chases the sell liquidity.
And then the volume drying off and price stabilizing.
So here we just had an example of that.
Price was actually, there's multiple examples within the same one.
You had price relatively stable, pumped out, dried off.
The same thing happens here, price is stable, pumped out, dried off.
And the same thing happened here where price was relatively stable,
price pumped out, dried off.
Now, the same way you have origin, move back to origin-ish,
you have origin move back to origin
and then you also have origin
move back to origin
how much were you willing to bet
that price will eventually come back to origin here
it almost always does
the same way we had
origin move back to origin
we have had countless origin
move back to origin down up
up down up down
right these are individually as price runs
why is this happening you have an area of stability
when trade is being facilitated
buys and sets of matching
and any volume
so there's sell equity
this buy liquidity
any volume market order buying
market order selling is not
great enough at those times to push price out
yeah right
here this low volume
period stability and volume
whilst liquidity
is kind of maintaining price stability
then you have a small
area of weakness
coupled with a volume shot price pumps out
creates that weakness
causes price to overstretch
and price subsequently ends up rebalancing back down.
This stability, dislocation, exhaustion, and fill.
So stability, dislocation, exhaustion, and fill
is consistently and repeatedly happening on an infinite basis.
As long as volume comes into these markets, this will always happen.
That's essentially the structure of how price moves.
It doesn't matter what scale.
it on that structure is present and that's the structure that we're going to be that we are breaking down
as of right now so even during this price run you had stability pop price comes back in stability
pop stability pop comes back in and it keeps doing it keeps doing it keeps doing it now think of this year
we have the bigger one the larger price run which ran out and came back to the origin yeah and that was
made up of smaller versions of stability come back in
stability come back in so stability pop come back in right
so you have these patterns repeating on
on all scales but the patterns have self-similarity they look the same
regardless of where you look at it on i could zoom into this
on the smallest of charts and you're going to see the same thing once it loads okay
so you have stability surge comes right back in stability
surge comes right back in
stability surge comes right back in
it doesn't have to be up and down by the way
it could be down and up
and then we had the larger one
so stability surge draws right back to origin
it's happening on a repeated basis all the time
so if that's the structure and how price moves
we break this structure down
trying to determine what the you know
imagine this is happening on a repeated basis
price will always draw out
dry off draw back in
these inefficiencies that are being created in the middle
and then the subsequent exhaustion at these highs
where we want to be entering
if that's the behavior that is a function of the structure of the market
it's always going to repeat it's super consistent
it makes sense to try and exploit that
if it's happening consistently
where is their edge
there's edge in something that's likely to work over time
repeatedly
and there's a higher probability of outcome
as we're discussing here
there's a high, all you need
is to go back and try to build some
basic experiences and
observations, this happens on a repeating
basis all the time, on an infinite basis
on all timeframes.
It doesn't matter if you're on the three-tick chart
or you're on the one-month chart, it's all
the same. There's obviously
differences, there's time differences,
the amount of distance price travels
on the one minute is completely
different to the one month, but
the behaviour visually is the same.
You're going to have stability, surge,
throw back in. And these again are results of the organizing principles we've discussed, market limit
order ratio, equity providers drawing away, avoiding taking on risk, liquidity disappearing,
and there's subsequent effects of all of that stuff. There's also other general principles
that apply, stuff like volume is not a constant. Yeah, variable volume flow. Yeah, the flow of volume
is just unrealistic to expect it to stay the same intensity
every single second.
This is a marketplace, right?
You have a bid and offer,
you have sellers of liquidity and buyers of liquidity.
It's unrealistic in any business
to expect the same level of intensity of customers buying liquidity.
So, you know, you're in a shop, you sell a milk.
It's ridiculous to expect a customer every minute.
Yeah, definitely.
You have variable customers.
flow as well. The same way you have variable volume flow. It's obviously much, much more frequent
the amount of volume that hits these markets, and it's much greater in size, but it's still
variable. You have periods where volume dries off. You have periods where there's high,
high, one-directional volume and sell weakness here. And again, the volume dried off,
price stabilized. Price pops out, stabilizes back in. Price pops out, becomes super inefficient,
leaves that weakness behind and draws right back in pops out draws back in now those are
smaller repetitions of stability dislocation and exhaustion and then you have the larger stability
dislocation exhaustion and fill right so all of these moves even that here if i looked inside of
it we're going to see stability dislocation fill stability dislocation fill stability dislocation fill
stability dislocation fill
it won't just be
sell, sell, sell, sell, sell.
It will sell low volume.
High volume, low volume.
Do you get it?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's because of these dynamics,
variable volume flow.
Liquidity dynamics where,
as a, LPs avoid taking on risk,
the amount of liquidity changes as well.
The transactional methods
in which we trade,
the broader characteristics of FX,
two-sided liquidity, high-level
of national demand,
combine all of those three things
the all of those multiple sorry variables together and you have this exact dynamic where price
consistently runs dries off runs dries off runs dries off again we're taking advantage of that
the good thing is at these points of exhaustion the these conditions are pronounced so at like
that area today where I took a short today um the liquidity is super super stretched on one side is
there's weakness and bids more so than they should be if the LPs didn't behave the way they did.
You can just imagine in this phase of phase this price run here.
This is A, this is B.
You had relative price stability or at least this whole area that was relative price stability.
Price sold off, left some weakness behind, relatively thinly traded, the real sell liquidity back up there.
price hits on buyers by liquidity any market order selling that was coming into the market was
absorbed by the buy liquidity right yeah so the market order selling is right off the buy
liquidity is there sucking down any buyers so imagine you wanted to buy here sellers have come here
there's not that many sellers there but they're hitting your level that you want to buy yeah
so those buy limits are present simultaneously we have
weakness and sell liquidity left behind
so there's gaps in that price run
any than new market orders that
come through they're going to push price
on the less liquid side so any market order
volume that comes through is able to
push price up right
now let me ask you so
there was a level
of buy liquidity here that
had 50
million buy limit
orders then you had this price run to the
downside where there was heavy
market order selling going on but little
liquidity little by liquidity low by liquidity by the point price reached down here there was only 10
million market order selling left what happened what we hit a thicker um a thicker area where there were
buyers in the market um so sell liquidity dried off got absorbed no no sell volume oh yeah okay okay yeah
sell volume dried off got absorbed in that area then the key word the keyword that you just said is absorbed so the market order selling 10 million market order selling hit the buy limit orders took 10 million of them yeah but this this 40 million outstanding now in terms of sell liquidity in this price run down it's left it thinly dispersed yeah think of it as as very very thick or relatively thick here
then on the way down
as it stretched out
it got thin
yeah
now let's just say
a random business
they just go
market order long
10 million
GDPUSD
and for example
there's only 10 million
stretched out
over this area of prices
yeah it would fill up until there then
so price fills
bam
but what about this 40 million then
the 40 million could have been pushed
higher. Okay. So this remains outstanding. Yeah. Somebody wants to trade that much. The likelihood of them
getting filled down here now is lower. Yeah. Yeah. Right. So obviously there's automated strategies and
there's automated ways in which volume and liquidity can be filtered out. There's one automated
execution algorithm which is floating, which means this floats a longward price. It travels with it. It follows
with it, it follows it. The aggressive one. Well, it's the one where you can set it to be aggressive.
Yeah, yeah. Right. So if it's on aggressive, it will place it very, very close or inside the
spread. If it's passive, it'll place it, for example, 10 pips away from the spread, right? But in either
case, it's floating and it follows it. It's called a floating iceberg. So typically what you'll get is
in these environments, after the origin has been picked up, the move down, the selling has dried off,
the selling has become weak,
there's relative weakness in sell liquidity
in this whole price run
with a real cause typically back at the origin
up there.
All right.
Now, once that price runs dried off,
we've hit a stronger area of a pose
and buy volume or by liquidity.
Price obviously draws off on light buying.
Because this remains outstanding,
you will usually see this
start to follow with price.
Yeah.
And this is how reversals take place.
The move down had, I don't know,
50 billion. They got filled here, 10 billion, 10 billion, small amounts, small amounts
until there was only 10 million left in this price run, right? It leaves this middle area
relatively thinly traded and the origin where the real sell liquidity should be and typically
is. So the selling is right off. We've hit an opposing area of stronger buy a volume and
buy liquidity. Sellers get absorbed. Light buying is able to push price up because of the
exhaustion and the weakness left behind and then subsequently we see these this liquidity start to
accept higher prices in order to get filled yeah if that liquidity wants to get filled is very like because
market orders if another market order from a different business came in that's a number 10 million
that will continue to drive prices higher anyway likely at least the further price moves away from
this original area of bi liquidity the less likely is to get filled so larger trade
is they don't typically trade in one area.
They have to accept their large volume
or their large trade is going to get filled over a range.
There might be a 20-pip range, 15-pip range,
but that's how large trades are filled.
For argument's sake, this is not a large trade in FX.
It could easily be 500 million, right?
But all I'm trying to illustrate here is
we had that market order, push price back up,
there's a thicker area of sell liquidity here
those thin dispersion of sell liquidity there
and like 10 million market order
from a completely random entity yeah
from a completely random entity
cause price to draw higher the 40 million then is forced to chase
and in this instance it starts to populate the bucket
so the market order buying buy and buy and buy it
the market orders dry off
yeah from the previous time
the market orders dry off it might hit some sell liquidity as well
but in this instance
as price dries off
it leaves behind that small
weakness in bids
light selling causes price
to run down
but any selling
quickly meets buy liquidity
why is that
by liquidity there
it's likely
we hit a huge area
of buy liquidity there
and now it's traveling
along with price
trying to get filled
yeah
do you get it
yeah that makes sense
so trade is facilitated
here for a while
low volume
light market order selling
light market order
buying price is quite stable there's a high likelihood that the bids are thicker than the sellers
why well in this instance we just picked up that large area of we just hit a level on the left
which we could anticipate this decent buy liquidity there and compare that to them this move down
which has traveled so far and it's filled filled filled filled filled picked up sellers picked up sellers
picked up sellers because of how far this price runs traveled
is we're going to look at characteristics inside of here
which is showing weakness but the point I'm illustrating here is
you could have had a huge volume shot
but it's been filled filled filled filled filled filled filled
until there's little sell liquidity left in this move now
did you get it yeah so sell liquidity got weaker the further
the price runs traveled and then we've hit
an opposing area of stronger by liquidity which is now being filled
so when price stabilizes into this low volume phase like this
they can still be weaker sell liquidity and stronger bi-liquity
but there's not enough volume to cause price to pop out yet
yeah you get it so I'll give you numbers and figures
so now we reach the stage we know that the bi-liquities except to higher prices
we know that this is going to hold sell liquidity in here
which I'll validate to you in a moment let's just say there's only 10 million
sell liquidity there
there's
40 million
holding price
by liquidity
here
but at any
given moment
only 1 million
market order
buy is coming in
only 1 million market
order sales
coming in
1 million buy
1 million sell
that's low volume
for now right
yeah
until the sell
liquidity here is depleted
and there's only
1 million left
right
it wouldn't even
take a huge
market order
to push price out
yeah it wouldn't
sometimes they can be a big market order
I'll be honest
another business could be like
okay now we need another 10 million of GDP
for whatever reason
and price shoots out
once this area of sell liquidity was cleared
the 10 million's gone
what's in the way to stop
what's in the way
where's the sell liquidity
that any buy volume can match with
we know there's plenty of buy liquidity
that market order sellers can match with
do you get it
What was that last thing you said there?
So there was 10 million sell liquidity here, yeah?
Yeah.
And there's 40 million buy liquidity here.
That's moved up.
And then within this period, there's low volume in the sense that a 1 million market order can come through, 9 million left, right?
Market order selling 1 million, 39 million left.
1 million buying, X million, you know, 8 million left.
Market order selling, 38 million left.
etc etc which side is likely to deplete first the sell side so once that sell liquidity here is gone
where would the next you know where does price have to go to find the next sell liquidity
lower or higher if i'm market order buying oh higher yeah right so any next next and the next
market order buy that comes through is going to have to go and find sell liquidity at the
next level yeah this is why price goes to less liquid side
Here, there's much thicker by liquidity, traveling along with price.
There's areas where the market order buying, there's one market order buy, one market order sell, it stabilizes.
The amount of customers in the market stabilize, the same way you could have 10 customers coming in your shop, buy milk.
For the next six hours, no customer comes.
You had volume shot from one customer, this business.
Then the volume dried off, but the liquidity, the buy liquidity was thick.
and the sell liquidity was what?
The sell liquidity that was thinner.
Exactly.
There wasn't necessarily enough volume
to push price out in any direction in this phase,
but there was still weakness on sell liquidity.
Right?
And then we subsequently get the next volume shot.
It could be not, let's just say it's not a business this time.
It's a pension fund.
They are trying to hedge 10 million pounds worth of dollars
worth of exposure,
so they need to short US dollar.
against GVP, so they buy GVP USD.
That next 10 million, it has to transact.
It's a market order long.
Yeah.
But where's the sell liquidity?
Well, it's not inside of here, so what does price do?
Yeah, it has to go further up to try and find it.
It shoots through it.
This volatility increases.
It starts to aggressively find the next area of sell liquidity, no?
Yeah.
If there's nothing, if I want to, let's just say, there's,
there's 10 lots on sale here
and there's one lot on sale there
I buy 11 okay I buy 10
cool the next one that I buy
market order is they're not going to push price
directly up to there instantaneously
yeah because there's nothing in between
exactly obviously in real trade bank
it's not that extreme there will be some
sell liquidity hence why there's never gaps in prices
there's always prices are always connected in FX
because there's always some liquidity
just not enough
but what you're seeing here is price accelerate
after this area of sellers were depleted
any market orders that came through
cause price to push continue pushing to the upside
and as we know
the dealers would have known this weak sell liquidity at this area
after it's been depleted
when that large volume shot came from the next customer
they then also avoid taking on short positions
other dealers have to control the supply of sell liquidity
so even if there was sell liquidity here
some dealers wouldn't have been able to offer it out to the market
they would have to control the distribution of sell liquidity
making this move even worse than it should be you get it
it makes it more inefficient than it should be
creating pronouncing the weakness present in that
in that leg so that one 10 million volume shot runs runs gets thinner and thinner and thinner and
thinner hits the area of sell liquidity let's just say there's only 5 million here because on the
way up 2 million was there 2 million was there 2 million was there do you get it sell liquidity 2 million
was there so some of the 10 million go down when it goes down goes down it gets thinner and
thinner and thinner until there's hardly any market order buys left the sell liquidity absorbs the
market order buys and the move up left such weakness behind where is the real liquidity can you
circle it where do you think this liquidity green went to did it did the green go up to there or in
this instance should be quite you know price is showing you where the liquidity went to exactly right
so price kind of just went to the last range that pushed price out sorry the liquidity kind
of just went to the last range that pushed price out and it stayed there it didn't follow that
thin price, that volatile
area of price, the
volatile condition of price where it was
moving aggressively. Here you would have
been seeing the tick frequency
so this, which is not
doing anything right now.
It got jumpy towards the top.
It would have been a bit more jumpy. It would have
been ticking more frequently.
But here it's hardly doing anything, right?
So the tick frequency,
the level of volatility present in the market is
much greater during these periods. The
willingness to transact at higher and higher prices
is less so
so there's a negative
correlation with the volatility and the willingness
to trade at those prices
whilst the real liquidity
moved up to here and just stayed there
once the market would have a volume
drop dried off hits some sell
liquidity drew down
restabilized with buy liquidity
as well again and then
that moved down was likely also
thinly traded
yeah
created that weakness this
plenty of buy liquidity here. The sell liquidity is here. Any light market order buyer pushes price
right up to where the sell liquidity is and price stabilizes again into low volume state.
So now the $40 million, let's just say some of it's grabbed here. And then we had some sell
liquidity here. There was only $5 million there. We know why price responded off weak sell liquidity
because the move up was exhausted by that point. The further this travel, the weaker it gets is
trading inefficiently so we don't actually need a strong sell liquidity level to push price down
considering that there's significant weakness in this leg here is trading so thinly
it's stretching that volume out that 10 million that 10 million sorry it's not trading
thickly it's actually getting stretched out like this like a chring cup there's breaks left
behind you get it yeah so the market order dries off hits on 5 million cell liquidity let's just say
at the high there was only
1 million left
so there's 4 million cell liquidity left
the 1 million has been absorbed by the 5
that makes sense
left behind weakness and sell by liquidity
there was traded thinly
there's gaps there's a vacuum of bi liquidity
any light volume shot causes price
to stabilise all the way back down
to wherever there is real
liquidity to transact with
now here
that light volume is very unlikely
to push past these buyers
any volume shot that comes in because of the move down
not trading in a significant way
with no buy liquidity there in the first place
we have a whole area of weakness especially in the move down
where is the sell liquidity is here
do you get it yeah
sell liquidity is here
by liquidity is there
any market order that comes through
immediately pushes price to wherever the sell liquidity
yeah do you get it
so price draws up to the sell liquidity
and the volume stabilizes again.
There's now 4 million sell liquidity.
Let's just say one million got taken off
in this next move up.
3 million sell liquidity.
Dozens of millions of buy liquidity.
The price still isn't moving through it.
Why?
Because the market orders,
there's only 200K market order by.
This buy liquidity is now moved up to here, by the way.
Because it's on an automated basis
traveling along with price,
trying to find fills.
It's trying to get filled.
Yeah.
So the volume is really,
dried off. Does it make sense what I mean by volume drying off? The driving force, which would
your market order that would eat the sell liquidity there is not eating it right now.
There's only 300K market order buy, for example. Yeah. 3K market order sell. 300K market order
buy, 2 million market order sell, but it still can't push past the buyers because it's much
thicker. Yeah. But when I said, you can have more selling than buying and price still goes
up because you
all you need it, you know, you could have
had 50 million being sold here
about 200 million by liquidity
only 10 million being
brought here, but only 3 million
sell liquidity. Price would go up now
even though there was
50 million sold
here.
So here you could have had easily
4 million being sold but it went
absolutely but fuck nowhere.
This 3 million was absorbed
300K, 200 K, 200 K, 200 K, 200 K,000, 200
300k market order long individually quick 10 orders now this area is depleted the next 1 million
market order that comes through it's not a huge amount market order buy bam price pumps right to the
next level yeah there was no further yeah are you follow what i'm saying what i just told you here is
that there was a more sell a larger sell order than the market order buying there was only 300k market
order buying there was a huge sell order of 4 million and price still didn't drop
because it was thicker bi-liquity and thinner sell liquidity.
Price pumped out after this area was cleared to the next level.
It ran thinly, not as inefficient as this run here, still relatively inefficient.
And the same behavior of bi-liquidity except in higher prices and chasing price is actually going on in here as well.
Look carefully.
Price runs, dries off, comes down by liquidity.
Runs, dries off, comes down by liquidity.
Run, strides off, comes down by liquidity.
So the same dynamic of bi-liquidity
except in higher prices
is also present in
the smaller legs inside of
the bigger one if that makes sense.
Okay, yeah.
Right, that's fractal, that's self-similarity.
And then this continues basically.
Now, what we call the area
holding the liquidity is inventory.
Okay.
All right, so as you can see here is,
buy volume stepped in and then we moved higher and since then all we saw is this push price to new highs
then the last range held push price to new highs push price to new highs push price to new highs the
last range out push price to new highs the last range held although we traded on it for a while
push price out and rather than returning back down as you can see in previous instances
you had buy liquidity price pushed out dried off and came back down yeah yeah pushed out it dried off
but it didn't fill why buyers accepted high prices it became more aggressive yes right buyer
buyers had a price up pushed out again and this is the first time today we've had the
showing signs of weakness in my opinion when you break this down to a lower time frames you'll see
that this was technically the last range
we technically broke it
and I also considered
there to be weakness because this area
was grabbed, grabbed, grabbed, grabbed,
just like
this shelf 10 million
in this cell, sorry, the 10
million in this area
here, the cell liquidity eat 10 million
it was eaten away, eaten away, eaten away, eaten away
and then price point for it once it was cleared.
So if this
one second,
So if this is inefficient price action, wouldn't this here be considered efficient price action?
Yes, on this scale that you're looking at price.
On the five minute, this is broadly efficient.
However, it has instances of inefficiency inside of it.
Think about it this way.
Over this 5.15, from 12 o'clock all the way till.
3.30, so 3.5 hours, it was efficient, broadly.
But at any individual given point in time, it was inefficient, yeah.
It could have been inefficient.
But because it was inefficient here, while it's broadly, it remained stable,
the inefficiencies were filled really quickly.
When this higher time frame, the five minute, became inefficient,
the inefficiencies were not filled quickly.
they actually remained thin for a longer period of time
and it travelled a much greater distance.
So here we're talking about environment.
Within efficient environments,
you tend to see that the smaller inefficiencies,
the micro inefficiencies, quickly solved.
And this goes back to the point M80 earlier.
People have a misconception that greater volatility is good.
But within this low volatile environment,
you had bare trades.
At least the consistencies in price behavior
there was a high level of consistency
and the frequency was also
there was a high
you know, it happened a lot
the behaviour is consistently
repeated over and over again
for a three and a half hour period
but as soon as the market became volatile
inefficient, directionally driven,
one-sided, thick by liquidity
times by strong by volume
coupled with weak sell liquidity
price drove, drove, drove, drove, drove,
drove hardly any periods of significant filling of inefficiencies,
much less capacity to be active trading here.
You only really had one trade, two trades.
You get it.
Yeah.
So that goes and it kind of validates one point.
People have a misconception about volatility.
The lower volatility environments are more favorable to trade because you can be more active.
You can have tighter risk, i.e. you can take trades of smaller levels,
which means higher risk reward.
And the consistencies in price behavior is greater than volatile, directionally driven markets,
which, in contrast, you have lesser or lower frequency of trades and a lesser, lower consistency
in price behaviors, i.e., we exhausted here, but we didn't fully fill. We exhausted here, we didn't
fully fill. We exhausted here, and there's now the, finally, we might fully fill. Now, I don't get,
I don't want you to be too worried about this environment here.
I want the price to expand for a bit.
This period I won't be trading,
but I know we're setting me up for the time
where price does eventually stabilised.
Okay, so let me just,
so in this area here,
yeah, would you,
so say if, for instance, you took along anywhere here,
like you said, that there's loads of trades within here,
Would you take it to the nearest cell inventory?
No, because here we need to validate what sell inventory is, yeah?
You're on about sell liquidity.
Oh, yeah, yeah, sell liquidity, yeah.
Cell liquidity, it can be present in various locations.
You come at the origin of this sell-off, no?
Yeah.
Or it could be in the middle of this set-off, which is a better level?
The origin or the middle.
Yeah, origin.
But both are the set-liquited.
you know yeah so sell liquidity is a broader type of or it's a broader or sell liquidity by
liquidity or simply liquidity base they're broader terms for where we can find areas of liquidity
but then there's types types are based on location uh yeah so types are based on location there's just
to give you insight into some of the ones you'll be learning there's shelf slash inventory
there's apex top or bottom
there's breakout accumulation
there's shifting point
each of these are liquidity bases
but just the specific type
just the same way you have
different models of cars
right or you have
yeah
so these are like different types
different locations
the reason we separate them is because each of these
have various
you say unique characteristics
they have unique characteristics
and they'll work in different environments
better than others if that makes sense.
And also to keep it,
you have residual levels of liquidity
and then inside residual
we have others as well.
But again, we're going to start to look into all of this.
You already know what core is.
Inventry is the liquidity
of this condition in the market
which is best described as
what is the consistent characteristic
in each of these instances that I've outlined?
every single time I said
this thicker buy liquidity
and I said this dinner
sell liquidity every instance
now
if obviously the buy volume
remained the same size throughout the price run
it would have just gone straight through it
as we said
volume is variable
so here you have low volume eating the sellers
and the buyers away and then the volume shot comes in
the volume dries off
price stabilises
then the volume shot comes in again
it stabilizes and then shot again low volume etc etc so even though it's a nuanced or it's a critical point to understand
it's a nuance even though there's weak sell liquidity and thick by liquidity it doesn't mean price is
constantly moving in that direction okay yeah actually even though this thick by liquidity down here
price extended out inefficiently as a result of the liquidity provider provider
the behaviours, the protection mechanisms, and also simply those weak sellers here,
price had to move to the next level to find wherever the next area of sell liquidity is.
But in doing so, it created that area of weakness in between where there wasn't any bioliquity
or hard any bi liquidity.
So once the market order buyers dried off, it didn't take that much selling to push price down.
Think about what that means.
Price is moving down in an environment with sellers a week.
prices moving you know broadly sellers were weak all throughout this move all today how did price then move down
because volume is not a constant volume is variable the volume initially here as it surged was strong
they got thinner and thinner and thinner as it was filled the further price travels the thinner it gets
the volume we know the effects of the price dynamics which create these weaknesses
and we know price needs liquidity to transact.
So the liquidity remains that remained in this instance down here,
there's a weakness in the middle,
volume dries off the further it travels,
creating the condition where there's less buy liquidity,
stronger sell liquidity,
and we know price goes at a less liquid side.
So it doesn't take that much selling to push price down.
Yeah.
Right?
In critical, you understand that.
That price can move against the strength.
It will move against.
the strength. Strength isn't necessarily market order buying, but it's more to do with the amount
of liquidity on one side versus the other. Price can move out here, but the real buy liquidity
is down there. What happens once the market order buying dries off? Rebalances. Any selling,
light selling, causes price to rebalance. That causes and creates a move against the strength of the
market.
So I forgot your point.
Sorry, what was your question?
Yeah, I said here that if you take a long, would you not take it until the next
sell inventory?
Oh, okay, yeah.
Then I went on to discuss what inventory is, right?
There is no sell inventory here, by the way.
Inventry is defined as the inventory, the stock, the
momentum liquidity of a directional move.
This is an environment where there's weak sell liquidity and strong bi-liquity.
So the behaviours we see is consistently the last buy base holds.
This is the last base that pushed price to new highs.
It held.
Even though price went down to it and we saw some selling and price moving down, still
it was a buyer's market.
Still there was bi-liquity thickness, sell liquidity, thinness.
and the last range that pushed price to new highs held.
So an inventory is the stock, the momentum liquidity of a directional move in an instance of imbalance.
So this is broadly imbalanced, buy strength, sell weakness.
No?
The inventory then is the last base that pushed price out where the inventory of liquidity
should be.
So look, here you had
buy liquidity, push price out,
price came down,
grabbed the buy liquidity,
that held.
Price ran out,
came back down,
the last range held.
Price ran out,
came back down,
last range.
This is the new range
that price ran out,
came back down,
formed a new range,
although you see,
this didn't push price
to new highs.
So that can't be the range.
This remains the range.
Price fed off it,
stabilized,
push price out to new highs the last range helped it just formed a higher one right no last range
broke here it just became a bit more aggressive the last range push price out and right now the last range
is technically still holding so inventory is what inventory is the last range holding yes the last range
that pushes price out or holds price yeah within an environment of imbalance that's the key here
you don't have inventory in that environment on that fractal area of stability
there is not a balance there is this stability in sellers and sell liquidity and bi-liquity
in theory if you forget the broader context around it there is no inventory in that
environment because this this sell liquidity hold a price down by-liquity hold a price
up price is stable it's not moving directionally right so this environment where we
see buy basis holding and weaks are liquidity it results in what price running out drying off price
still draws back down we still see selling against the strength but each buy base holds that's
the key characteristic here okay can you identify the last buy base uh yeah let me just uh not be somewhere
here okay so for now i'll agree um that's
the last buy base what's the last buy base here right did the last buy base hold yeah i didn't go past it uh where's
the new by base here yeah there this environment is because of what there's thick biiquity
yeah thin cell liquidy yeah thin cell liquidy so when volume comes in it pushes to the less liquid side
it quite easily pushes the less liquid side when volume comes in the direction of the less liquid
liquid side, it sets off
chain reaction type responses from
equity providers which avoid adverse selection
which kind of pronounce that weakness
on one side of the market. They make those
moves worse.
Or they make those moves more inefficient.
So this environment
broadly is called mid-flow.
It's just a single stage
of a price run. It's present
at every single price run. It's the
mid-flow stage. There's different
temposal rhythms and variations of
midflow but the overriding characteristic here is the buy basis hold in bullish midflow in bearish
midflow the cell basis hold the state of liquidity of midflow is one-sided liquidity or one-sided
weakness still variable volume flow applies to mid-flow i.e. you can have strong buy liquidity
here it's weak sell liquidity there price run out to
the less liquid side, the market orders can dry off and price can still move against the
strength because of where the liquidity is, creating moves against the broader strength of the
market.
That's why direction in the market, in my opinion, is less significant.
I don't give two fucks about where the market's going.
I care about how it's getting there.
If the market ends up from here today and tomorrow are there, it's very unlikely to move
move to the in a straight line why because of variable volume flow did it today move in a straight
line no it had multiple points with a buying dried off multiple points with a buy and dried off
even though it was a broader phase of mid-strength it was mid-flow it was relatively efficient
mid-flow like you said the characteristics are quite observable here by basis held every single
time, but we still had highly consistent corrections and price drawing back into range against
the inefficiencies, which is a significant realization to make.
The direction doesn't matter in FX.
That's why I don't call this a trend, by the way.
I don't call it a trend because it implies that price moves into a certain direction,
when in reality, the market orders dry off, it creates weakness in the middle of these areas,
price rebalances through those weaknesses
that is an effect of the
microstructure of the market
like I said the markets are efficiently
inefficient this price run
it had a huge amount of volume transacted in buying
there was a huge amount of buying going on today
in pound
huge hundreds of billions of transacted long
but there was areas of inefficiency
where the buying was so so stretched out
the liquidity was left behind so far away
it didn't take much selling to push price down.
Price had to stabilize, the price had to rebalance to find buy liquidity before it could take on this next move.
Volume dried off profusely today, frequently today.
This is the point I'm stressing.
We trade or the behavior in price doing this is more predictable than it is for you to say,
this large byside firm is going to take a bullish view on the pound because they think Boris Johnson's a good leader.
or they think the central banks, you know,
that's gay macro model.
We don't do that shit.
We don't make predictions in an environment
which has dynamic probabilities.
Don't get me wrong,
there is times where you can make longer price predictions.
You've seen me do it with ripple.
Yeah, right?
There is times, depending on the broader environment,
price being in the right condition,
being in the right stage.
You'll come to identify those instances over time.
But you as an active day trader
that wants to be at-chart state trading,
consistently, you need edge
these behaviours that I'm discussing where
price exhaust, price draws back into range
are a function of the microstructure
that we've discussed time and time and time again
and this is where edge is given.
The market provides edge in
being inefficient. Just the same way
court siding this
edge in knowing information before
the... Everybody knows
that information at the tennis court
but me and you were taking advantage of how
slowly is embedded into price
into the odds
here we're taking advantage of
the liquidity providers
creating these weaknesses
and obviously price going to less liquid side
is guaranteed
or not
price going to less liquid side is guaranteed
these behaviours are highly
highly consistent
all you have to do is validate them
validation itself is another topic
that we'll have next session
it'll be centred around how your brain learns
what internalisation means
building
but basically building
intuition and stuff, but validation you can just simply start out with, go back on any time frame
on any chart, the same behaviors exist. To finalize, we don't call these trends for this primary
reason that during this period, we had multiple points of bid exhaustion, market order
exhaustion, buying, and the volume flow is variable. It's not a constant. It's not constant
buy, buy, buy, buy, buy, buy, buy. It's actually
buy, buy, buy weakness.
Leaving behind weakness in bids.
Any selling pushes price down.
And then the volume is low.
Then you have surges of volume and the same pattern repeats
over and over and over again.
We take advantage of that.
Now, don't get it, like, it might seem like these are small
moves. We don't take advantage of these ones.
Who the fuck wants three pips, bro?
Yeah, no.
But this, I'm just trying to
to show you even on the lower lowest of time frames yeah the same applies even on the highest
of time like the big enough time frames the same applies so hopefully there's more color to what
we're doing here at least in midflow i'm obviously going to set you on an assignment
you need to start building your sample sets of at least observations of price swings so
keep that
annotation that you made
schematic, sorry,
keep that schematic that you made
last week.
I was just
get some other ones
and try to explain things
in different ways.
Like I said,
I think your point three
we're priced left behind a vacuum.
You need to elaborate on that.
You could also identify
what low liquid state means
and da-da-da-da-da.
How like you can have
sell liquidity and buy-liquity
you can have really significant weakness in sell liquidity
and price still doesn't break through
because the volume, the market order volume
is for now not coming yet.
You could make a chart that identifies periods of low volume
and periods of relative means in comparison to high volume.
And also you could draw a distinction between how
this is higher volume selling but traded thinly.
Low volume traded but high unfulfilled.
volume.
But that's separate, right?
The assignment task is I want you to identify three, sorry, two examples of midflow.
Okay.
And annotate everything from the state of liquidity of the midflow, the strength and the weakness.
The individual price swings, I want you to explain to me how just because there's, you know,
there was weakness here and strength here.
Why did price not break through?
What happened when price did break through?
The sell liquidity was depleted.
The volume shot came in.
mean shot could be from anybody, the liquidity that the $40 million on field can be one firm,
the market order that comes through can be from a separate, entirely unassuming, separate
firm that causes price to go to a less liquid side. I'm going to discuss where price goes against
them the strength of midflow, and I want you to identify the features of midflow, the buy basis
holding or the cell basis are holding. Just do one charge, but in as much detail as possible.
it can be on any time frame and some of the midflows you'll find won't hold all the buy bases uniformly and we'll discuss what that means later so try to find one that does hold all the buy bases all of them or cell bases yeah like this period here it held every single one all right so that's the the assignment task i just want to obviously check how you're seeing these things in charts you're building a sample set it might seem pointless but you are building a visual framework at least or a
a visual, you're visually building experiences of what these price behaviours look like and also
what they mean. Why is it that buy basis continuously hold? Why is it that even though this is a bullish
trend that prices go against the trend, variable volume flow. Inventry. We know why the buy liquidity
is there and not accepting higher and higher prices. Well, it is accepting high and higher prices,
but why it's not doing it super aggressively is because of the way the liquidity
is being filtered out through these automated strategies
or through these automated algorithms.
Right?
So yeah, we're now going into the realm
of explaining price behavior, why it occurs,
where there's consistencies,
and this is just one environment.
There's multiple environments.
How many different environments are there?
So this is the thing.
You can have midflow,
which is a broad environment.
It happens very consistently,
but there's different levels of tempo.
There's different tempos and rhythms.
So there's ones that are highly inefficient
There's ones that are relatively efficient
They have significant differences between them
Then you have obviously
So yeah
Mid-flow is a state of imbalance
That's technically what the environment is
And there's different tempos and rhythms of the imbalances
And then there's other stages for price
Which is apexes
Apexes or cores
Which are the origins of moves
They're obviously stable areas
of price. But then, yeah, they're really the main two. But like I said, there's different
variations and different tempos and rhythms. There's different timeframes that are happening
as well. So imagine this is a one-hour chart, right? This on the one-hour chart will be
super efficient stable. And then inside of here, sorry, this on the one-hour chart is inefficient,
right? Relatively driven, it's imbalanced. The biobases are holding, sell equities we can be seen
buy volume push price up.
But on the lower time frame,
this will be super stable and efficient.
That will be, that will be.
And this on the lower time frame as well
will not necessarily be directionally driven.
It might actually form efficiently.
So depending on the time frames,
it also brings a level of,
it can affect the types of trades we see.
So even though there's a small number of environments,
it's definitely a high,
high, you know, wide variety of,
them. Each of the varieties can have an effect on the behaviors you'll see. Each of them you have
to be experienced and experience the differences between them. So yeah, it's not as straightforward as
it seems, basically. But like I'm saying here, but not in the realm of trading price. You're not trying
to trade price. You're trying to connect with why price behaves the way it is, be able to interpret it
in the first place. So later we can, you know, you might be a midflow trader that trades it amazingly
well. You might be the best midflow trader ever. But first, for you to, you know, identify which
environment you trade well and you have to be able to at least read prices in the first
place. Here we're discussing why prices form and look the way they do. We've only discussed
one environment of bullish midflow in a bit of detail and we've already discussed that in midflow
there has to be weakness on one side, strength on the other, hence why the base is hold.
Yeah. Do you get it? Yeah, yeah, yeah. Think about it this way. Final point. If there was not
buy liquidity here, then
price with any selling would a push price
down. It's as simple as that.
But there had to be,
it's the way in market trades,
they had to be by liquidity
holding price up
in each of these instances.
When the market order sellers push
price down, they had to
be by liquidity there to absorb the market
order sellers.
When price pushed out here
and dried off, they had
to be exhaustion in market order buying
even if there was weak sell liquidity there
there had to be exhaustion and the volume
it's impossible for it to be
you know you get it so
we're explaining why price behaves the way
through this liquidity prism
prism being like this
the shades of the lenses we're seeing the markets through
when viewed through this prism
it gives us access to a whole level of depth
and yeah it gives us access
to a whole level of depth
which then further shows us
like a different world to trading prices
where you can trade more accurately
you can trade more precisely
you can trade more appropriately
for the environment
you can differentiate between all the different environments
you get it so we
we like I don't know
man if ICT
was looking at the market
through fucking Raybans fake Turkish
Raybans we're looking at it through fucking I don't know
Chanel 10s bro
McCartier Frings
yeah right this is an upgraded version of looking at
prices, which is more appropriate considering the amount of various environments that exist,
the different levels of volatility, all of which throw traders off.
This is why traders will do well for four weeks.
Suddenly the environment changes to get bombed and they lose the last four weeks of profit
and the rest of their account.
The market is too dynamic.
It's changing all of the time.
There's various environments.
Price formation is a function of volatility.
Price formation is a function of liquidity.
Price when it goes up, if there was a market order greater than the available
sell liquidity and vice versa etc because of these organizational rules we can always explain what
price is doing price subsequently then reflects the state of liquidity that's actually a principle
price reflects state of liquidity we're going to use that principle to manage our trades to to
work out if our trades or if my entry is if i'm right about my trade if i'm wrong about my trade
when to cut your trade as well when to cut our trade
this is a superior principle that applies robustly regardless of what the market is doing.
So, yeah.
Yeah, so I would take it that, say if in midflow, well, about a midflow that's bullish at that time,
if the last buy base was broken, then you could, depending on how price is setting up,
that you could probably cut your position.
If you were long.
yeah yeah that's that's crucial information but we're going to basically find how at the end of price swings let's say it's a bullish price swing we will see the last buy base break there'll be technical break so I would consider this to be a technical break and I don't think you broke anywhere else yeah we could call that technical so we'll find that towards the end of a price swing
during the price swing formation
there was obviously
bid strength to sell weakness
but then that volume
it's not infinite
the liquidity that's holding price off
is also not infinite
that liquidity weakens
at one point
price will show us
that weakness will typically proceed
the parabolic spike phase
and then we'll typically get the reversal
this not one here
is this
here
oh why is it doing that for
sorry um where was i trying to yeah yeah is that not didn't this come lower than that
no no but that didn't push to new highs oh yeah yeah yeah you're right you're right yeah yeah
understand then it pushed the new highs but it being technical about it this did push price
the new highs and then price broke that red box anyway so technically yeah but um there's conflicting
scaled hit at play here
this is a one hour price swing
inside of a daily price swing
in reality the daily price swing
clearly
clearly showed weakness here
massive move out
we broke it
then we run on that parabolic
phase but preceding that
by base is holding quite well
we start to show weakness
higher time frame swings
think about it if this is a daily swing
each kind of represents a day
that represents 24 hours individual
it's going to take much longer for it to finish if the next one is a one minute price swing
each candle just represents one fucking minutes 60 seconds the frequency of these one minute swings
will be much greater and higher yeah so ending on the time frame of the swing we're going to have
relatively like different ways of approaching them but the characteristics are the same whether it's one
minute or two fucking years it's all this